this is an elite level this is one of
the top bodybuilders in the world with
arguably the best core the sport has
ever seen and he is getting a full
workout in in basically what you can do
in almost any holiday in he does a big
hitch in his deadlift which is very
reminisent of Derrik Poundstone it's
really cool to see how he REM Maneuvers
his positioning to actually get to
lockout Rob Carney is an absolute Beast
he's the strongest tested raw 120 kg
male in the world right now hey folks
welcome to strength weekly the weekly
YouTube internet digital on your phone
show that brings you everything you need
to know from around the barbell game my
co-host Phil Blackman agrees with me I'm
David Thomas Tower we're bringing this
to you from Barb ben.com and uh little
teaser at the end Phil's going to talk
about the most anabolic meal ever is it
called the garbage plate is it native to
Rochester New York we'll get to that but
you're goingon to have to watch the
entire episode to find out Phil we have
lots of big stories happening might as
well dive into the Run of show we have a
massive retirement announcement from one
of the most well-known strongman
athletes in the world we have a 500 lb
deadlift triple done with one hand we're
going to talk about who why what where
maybe most importantly how then we talk
about potentially the strongest nons
super heavyweight raw powerlifter in the
world and why his recent deadlift double
might signal momentous things for
powerlifting in 2025 so we're going to
be looking ahead to the Future here and
last but certainly not least men's
physique Champion Ryan Terry shares a
great arms workout on the road we're
going to talk about why that's important
and look summer's coming up people want
their Beach bods but they're also going
to be traveling a lot what lessons can
we take from this for staying fit with
minimal equipment maybe working out in
hotel gyms Phil let's get right into it
maybe the biggest story leading up to
World's Strongest Man besides
predictions Rob Kerney multi-time world
Strongest Man competitor with a storyed
career 15-year career in the sport has
announced his retirement after the 2024
edition of the World's Strongest Man now
need to put a big disclaimer here Rob
Kerney is a friend of barbin he has
contributed to barbin he's written for
us he's been on our podcast multiple
times someone we've done videos with uh
part of that's because Rob is just a big
personality and kind of all over uh the
strength Sports World especially a few
years ago and was making a big impact
not only on the field of play so to
speak but off in trying to shift the
culture of strength Sports it is
difficult to sum up everything Rob has
done because his impact has been
extraordinary both as an elite
competitor and also like I said in the
culture of strength Sports so uh Phil we
should just give like the 10,000 foot
view here who is Rob Kerney you've been
covering strongman for a long time give
us your rundown of Rob as an athlete he
began strongman in 2009 he actually had
a background in CrossFit before that
which is kind of interesting what are
some career highlights that people
should know when they think of this guy
so yeah Rob Kerney is an absolute
monster in the space of strongman and
has had a pretty solid career given that
it's going to come to an end after this
2024 world strongest man so some of his
highlights this just most recently at
the America strongest man he was on the
podium he took in 2023 he's got a slew
of podiums all the way down across his
career he won the 2017 giants live North
American open that's one of the
highlights where he actually won Gold he
won the 2019 Arnold Australia contest
that's probably the biggest win of his
career and he is known for uh what I
find to be one of the most entertaining
types of deadlift to watch if you ever
watch him deadlift heavy against the
other bigger athletes on the world stage
he does a big hitch in his deadlift
which is very reminiscent of Derrik
Poundstone and it is awesome to watch
like if you've never deadlifted yourself
in that way go check out Rob Kerney pull
a heavy heavy deadlift it's really cool
to see how he REM Maneuvers his
positioning to actually get to lock out
Rob Kerney is an absolute Beast now Rob
for his entire career has been one of
the smaller Elite level open category
strong men you know who are competing
internationally he's about 510 about 280
pounds so he's shorter than a lot of his
competitors and he's also over a 100
pounds lighter than a lot of his
competitors so one thing that was always
interesting about Rob and watching his
career he was fantastic but he was doing
this at a significant size disadvantage
a few things robs was was known for
prodigious overhead strength it was in
the conversation for potentially setting
an alltime world record for the log
press he used a split jerk technique for
the log press one of the we actually see
that becoming a little bit more common
now Rob was one of the folks to really
Pioneer that in the open category of
strongman so Rob is coming off of and
was wrapping up a pretty storyed career
like I said an international Arnold CL
classic win a slew of Podium finishes
both in the US and abroad Rob's also
known for a couple other things in the
sport of strongman he was one of the
most prominent uh for his entire career
openly gay competitors in the sport of
strong man actually across strength
Sports and use the handle world's
strongest gay on social media now I
don't know if anyone ever truly
challenged that because as far as I know
uh he was the strongest openly gay
strongman competitor in the the world so
no one ever came at him and was like oh
you're not the strongest you're not the
strongest gay competitor in the world I
am he uh kind of was like the Dennis
Rodman of strong man when it came to
hairstyles would sport like a rainbow
Mohawk which was Dope by the way rainbow
beards and stuff oh yeah oh yeah rainbow
beards like fat from from from like
multicolor leggings to like the rainbow
Mohawk and beer like Rob showed up and
was a lot of f you knew where he was on
the competition floor yeah like you knew
who it was just look where the colors
look where the colors yeah yeah yeah um
Rob was really very much wearing his
heart on his sleeve and wearing his
identity on his sleeve and being very
open about that in a time you know in
2015 14 15 16 when that was a pretty
bold move and frankly Rob got a lot of
hate on social media back then I
remember some of the first times we
posted about him Rob collaborated with
barbin on a on a pride month article and
social media post years ago I remember
Barb Ben lost a bunch of followers
because of it like there were really
nasty comments I think we've seen the
culture of strength Sports shifting and
a big part of that is Rob's
outspokenness for lack of a better term
and I don't mean outspokenness in like
an annoying way I mean outspokenness in
like a way where he's just like hey this
is who I am and we existed in in these
spaces but also the fact that his
competitors rallied around him and we
talk about the community of strongman a
lot right it's a very small community of
folks in these Elite categories they're
always competing against each other
spending a lot of time together they
were so incredibly welcoming and
supportive of Rob that it really
signaled from the top down from the
elites this is we like we are very very
accepting of Rob we want strongman to be
a more accepting place for people all
Stripes backgrounds beliefs orientations
Etc and I really have to credit that as
having a bit of a domino effect and I
think the sport right now culturally is
in a very different place than it was
even five or six years ago I will get
off my high horse and I'm curious as to
your thoughts Phil yeah I think you'd
hit the nail on the head I think that
like you it's so hard to just to
articulate specifically the spots where
Rob has shifted the culture in the
strength Sports space but his impact is
most definitely felt like the if you if
we look back at where the world was a
handful of years ago to where it is now
there's no doubt that in the strength
Sports space that Rob kerney's impact
has definitely made a difference like we
hope that we will see him around the
strength sport game even if he's not a
competitor because his impact is
Monumental Monumental and we've been
covering for him for a long time we've
worked with him for a long time it is
hard to overstate what he has done for
the Space Trail bazer Rob Kerney calling
it a career hopefully we'll see him in
the announcers booth and still involved
in strength Sports on the media and
coaching side
Rob cheers to a career moving on to seg
two Yousef adessa bodybuilder
powerlifter uh we haven't really wasn't
really on our radar this guy wasn't
really on our radar right well we showed
he's got some Elite grip strength a
500lb one-handed deadlift for three with
no straps no straps here's the thing the
one-handed deadlift is impressive it's
cool it's not a competition lift right
there aren't like super modernday
records but I do want to go back to the
history book some recent history and
some history way back when to
contextualize the one-hand deadlift and
remember you have did this for a triple
but he was like straps no I got fingers
I got lifting straps built in in fingers
ever heard of them are they good enough
for you everybody buying all this gear
if we want to talk about true records
for a one-handed deadlift you got to go
back to October 8th
1920 almost 124 years ago according to
the Guinness Book of World Records a
German performer named Herman gner
unofficially so even this is unofficial
set the record for the right-hand bar
deadlift one-handed deadlift at 330
kilos or about 727 a half pounds
officially recorded later on the record
at 301 kilos or 6635 pounds so that is
the heaviest non- strapped one-handed
deadlift we have ever heard of so it g
to go back almost 104 years now let's
talk about some recent strapped
one-handed deadlifts Chris Duffin who
has deadlifted with straps 1,000 pounds
for multiple reps squatted 1,000 lbs for
multiple reps he one-handed deadlift
495b for five Larry Wheels deadlifted
585 lbs one-handed strongman Ivan
macarov reportedly pulled 595 pounds on
video one-handed but they all use straps
Adesa did not use straps just a hook
grip and I gotta say this is one of the
most impressive Feats of Strength of
grip strength that I have personally
seen in my time with barbend which is
the entire time with barbend because I
started barbend so
in the past eight years I haven't seen
any grip feet that I would call
significantly more impressive than this
Phil what are your thoughts yeah I think
so and also particularly that uh Adisa
doesn't have any competitive
powerlifting accolades we reached out to
him he he has not competed in
competitive powerlifting but he did tell
us what his one rep max is and uh we
might have to call the Guinness Book of
World Records his one rep max deadlift
is 785 lbs now that's not single-handed
but like you said you put a pair of
straps on this guy and he should he I
mean are we inviting him to the world
deadlift championships like are we in
that space like this is this is uh Mark
Felix level levels of grip strength on a
500 pound triple if I were Yousef this
is you know I'm gonna speak directly
youse just a little direct
address the world record one-handed
deadlift according to Guinness is in the
600s assuming you could do more for a
single than you could for a
triple interesting it interesting we're
just saying we're just saying it's
interesting youf it's interesting well
you know what's cool world records world
records and if you do if you call up gu
Brook of world records and then you get
that plaque they'll say you are
officially amazing and that's pretty
cool oh man I could use that kind of
validation I'm an elder Millennial so I
could definitely use that kind of
validation look folks this is not a
record this is something that's darn
cool and that's the thing about just
really cool it's not just records it's
not just retirements we're also bringing
you the darn cool the impressive
the disappointing the darn cool
everything in between speaking of
deadlifts would you mind taking this in
for the next segment just things up
absolutely Rondell hunt he lifts in the
120 kgam class and he deadlifted 400 kgs
raw for a double which is 4 a half kilos
over the ipf world record why does it
matter well he scored 3975 kilog at the
usapl raw Nationals and hasn't yet
reached the Benchmark of a 400 kilogram
pull in competition that means that next
time he competes if he calls for this
kind of weight on the bar he's going to
set a new ipf world record and as we
just talked about in the previous
segment we love that they're awesome
world records are sweet and Ronda hunt
like if I'm a Gambling Man David not
that not that I am but if I were I'm
putting all my chips on Rondell hunt to
crack a an ipf world record deadlift in
his next meet the thing about Rondell is
he's actually in the top 10 for total in
the total for tested lifters for tested
raw lifters in the world and he's the
only one in that top 10 the only man in
that top 10 who is not a super
heavyweight which is important that
means he's the strongest tested raw 120
kgam male in the world right now
effectively and you got to think with
his continued progress is he going to be
able to maybe crack the top five in
tested raw totals in the
world as a non-s super heavy which would
be super super darn impressive it would
be super impressive you say that his
training total is a th000 kilos which is
21 a half kilos over the current ipf
total world record held by Dennis
Cornelius so I mean the the range that
you're talking about isn't like some oh
is it you know with in the possibility
of our future are we maybe in that
timeline no that's like where his
training currently is he just needs the
lifting platform to prove it let's talk
about this 400 kilogram double and by
the way uh uh Rondell is from Trinidad
and Tobago so not a name we hear a ton
in powerlifting but he's certainly
repping uh he was lifting in a hot
environment this is kind of was this a
double or is this a two back to back
singles in quick succession maybe the
lad because he does a single raw with a
hook RP a rep at 400 kilos takes a
second grabs straps straps up without
much rest and then pulls it again
now I believe him he said he was
training a very hot environment sweat is
obviously the enemy of grip and he
needed to grab those straps because his
grip was slipping I get that I get that
hot humid not good for hook grip he also
said that he actually prefers lifting
without scraps because they change his
positioning now if you've ever
deadlifted heavy whis straps in a hook
grip position it does actually change
your positioning slightly and at these
Monumental weights even a slight change
in position makes a difference so some
folks actually straps obviously help
with your grip but they actually can
hurt your positioning when it comes to
the pull Rondell one of those lifters
who recognized that I thought it was
interesting it was interesting Insight
he's like listen straps help my grip and
I need the straps cuz it was sweaty the
bar was slipping but at the same time my
the rest of my positioning like my
posterior chain my active how I'm
actually executing the pull from a
non-rip perspective I prefer not using
straps hook gripping into a bar and
strapping into a bar it does place your
hands your forearms your arms in
slightly different positioning and I
think that's a really good takeaway here
and I appreciate him highlighting that
straps are not they they do help you but
they can also hurt you because they can
alter the optimal positioning through
your pool so I thought that was a good
takeaway something we don't hear about a
lot like wind supportive equipment can
actually be a detriment um so I
appreciate Rondell shouting that out I
think it's important to know this is
high level stuff high level it's high
level it's it's very inside baseball but
it is cool to see where it's at and if
you if you anybody who's who's watching
this go check out the video of Rondell
actually pulling this this lift you'll
see the amount of time that he spends
between reps is actually pretty minimal
it's it's very similar to like what a
strong man might do in a loading medley
like he deadlifts he runs off to grab
straps he runs back and he deadlifts
again like it's not like he's breathing
he's not you know re chocking or
anything so it's as close to a double as
you can get with maybe you know a red
light going on in in the judges judges
Booth all right well let's move on to
our last segment of the day Ryan Terry
the men's physique Olympia Champion
recently shared a travel work I did on
the road is about 45 minutes long an
arms and Core workout and Phil I wanted
to highlight this one because this when
traveling right travel it's tough to
stay in your routine you might not have
as much time you might struggle you know
might be a hotel gym or a gym without
the wage and Equipment you're used to
how am I going to get a hypertrophic
response if I'm don't have access to
heavy weights or the equipment you know
the equipment I want I really like what
Ryan Terry did here because he used a
few principles and we'll run us I'll ask
you Phil if you can run us through the
workout he used a few principles when it
comes to muscle building and when it
comes to optimizing for muscle building
and also optimizing for time in the gym
that I think can be applied to almost
any travel workout even if you're in a
hotel gym with minimal equipment Phil
can you run us through the workout real
quick yeah so uh see if you can get the
uh highlighted words here along the way
so he does a giant set of ghd crunches
Prater curls oblique crunches and
parallel bar dips he then does a super
set of cable tricep pushdowns and rope
curls and then a super set of weighted
crunches and oblique crunches David can
you guess the most important aspect of
the workout that was just listed the
most important aspect there's so many
that we're gonna go into then let's
let's go into them because I feel like
they don't jump off the page if you're
not as we were talking about super
inside baseball and they are very
valuable if you are traveling on the
road so I think the concept of we talk
about super sets a lot but let's talk
about giant sets
Phil what what did Terry do here as far
as a Giants because giant sets are
something I kind of forget exists but
they're also something that when I
remember and I do them if I'm crunched
for time or I don't have much equipment
are some of the most effective things
you can do so run us through this GI
this giant set which might be a less
familiar than a super set for folks so
if somebody knows what a superet is
which is just combining two workout or
sorry two exercises together and just
doing them without rest between each one
then think of a giant set as just
doubling that up a giant set is four or
more exercises in a circuit altogether
without rest it is also meant to be uh
timed for efficiency it improves the
pace of your workout and it in usually
increases like if you think like the
areas of a workout that you can change
you can change your frequency you can
change your volume and you can change
your load and the frequency is just the
amount of time that you're spending uh
how frequently you go to the gym how
frequently you train giant sets really
up the volume and uh get that heart rate
elevated and it's a way to you know if
you only have so much time while you're
on the road before you have to like
travel again doing giant sets or super
sets is the way to get in all of that
work and he's still alternating what
Terry's doing here is like a superet
he's still alternating muscle groups
right so suets are often doing you're
not doing the same muscle group back to
back because of that you can still uh
though it's more metabolically
challenging you can still maintain like
strength right you're not doing two you
know exercises back toback that attacks
the same muscle groups right I thought
this this giant set was interesting
because he's doing an
abdominal exercise the ghg crunches then
moving on to biceps uh targeting biceps
through the preacher curvs then moving
to oblique crunches so going back to
abdominals and then moving to parallel
bar dips which is challenging the
triceps chest but he's always
alternating so he's not taxing the same
muscle group back to back so it's a
principle of a superet two super sets
tack together to get maximal efficiency
for how much volume you're doing in a g
short period of time while also still
applying some of the principles of the
super set now giant sets are extra
taxing super sets are tough giant sets
are twice as difficult because you're
base not twice as difficult but your
you're going for more time without rest
however this seems like a cool a a darn
cool giant set and something you could
adapt to even work out on a hotel gym
right yeah the the aspect of this giant
set is all you need for this giant set
more or less is any hotel gym is
probably going to have at the bare
minimum a set of dumbbells and a weight
bench and outside of like the parallel
bar dips where you'd have to make an
adjust you'd have to adjust it to work
on the bench you can more or less do
this with just a dumbo rack like this
entire thing could be done so it's it's
not too far off from like the Baseline
minimum of what you would see in even
the you know smallest of Hotel gyms yeah
you can change that to you know bench
dips instead of parallel bar dips right
perfect example um okay let's move on
the next Super set was something also I
see this in a lot of Hotel gyms they
might have a cable machine single cable
setup maybe a double cable setup cable
tricep pushdowns and rope curls right
that is a super set very traditional arm
blasting super set here right Phil I
don't think it's more classic than this
no this is this is also one where when
you focus on this you do a couple rounds
of this super set you will get that pump
like that is good Progressive overload
keep that in mind you want to increase
the weight if you're looking for a
hypertrophic response but like yes this
is just like ABC you know just good
muscle building technique tricep push
Downs rope curls like you need you need
no space if they have a cable machine in
the hotel you're staying at this is the
one that's just like easy peasy you know
all right then Terry finished off with
another Super set of weighted crunches
and oblique crunches pretty classic way
to finish off the core uh get some you
know great
abdominal abdominal movement here um
look listen why we highlighted this
workout this is a workout you can do in
basically any hotel gym right now
obviously he used things like parallel
bars he used things like cable machine
you might not have parallel bars sub the
dips for uh bench dips right cable
machines a lot of Hotel gyms have cable
machines now a lot of Hotel gyms have
cable machines but you know what there
other things you can do a decent sub for
this could be like neutral grip pull-ups
if that's available if they don't have a
cable machine neutral grip pull-ups and
uh Skull Crushers right decent sub for
that all have to say this is an elite
level this is one of the top
bodybuilders in the world one of the top
the top maybe the top physique
competitor in the world with arguably
the best core the sport has ever seen
and he is getting a full workout in in
basically what you can do in almost any
holiday in right
and I don't know I need that little bit
of info Phil I got a big stretch of
travel coming up in a few weeks I'm
gonna be on the road for almost three
weeks in a row and I need a little inspo
I'm not going to have access to my
normal kettle bell fun you know Kell
sports stuff that I do uh maybe I'll do
a little hypertrophy block and I'm not
gonna look like Ryan Terry but using
these principles I can get in get out
and under 45 minutes and uh look a
little better for it and be done and
just a reminder everybody who's doing
all these weighted crunches and oblique
crunches remember that your abdominals
are a muscle like any other muscle don't
be speeding through those you want to
you want to you want to shorten the
muscle when you do the contraction when
you're doing your concentric portion of
the phase you want to shorten the
abdominals to actually get yourself up
that when you shorten the abdominals
your spine will Flex that's if you're in
flexion and that's how you do it like
just my muscle connection fam just a
nice little reminder as as we get into a
beat season mind muscle connection fam
that is the best ending to anything oh
Phil by the way uh you were in Rochester
recently you ate a garbage plate what is
a garbage plate so let me explain to
everybody what a garbage plate is
imagine that if you had uh nachos with
literally anything that you wanted on it
think of anything whether it's meat
whether it's uh chicken any any kind of
protein on top with all the different
kinds of sauces all the different kinds
of veggies like if it if you could make
nachos dump anything you wanted on it
but then instead of chips you used
french fries or tater tots or sweet
potato fries or macaroni salad or
literally any other carb you can think
of and let me tell you if you go to the
gym and you get your pump on and then
you go crush a garbage plate you won't
fit through your front door it's
awesome and on that note folks stay
anabolic for Barb ben.com and for
strength weekly I'm David Thomas to
joined by Phil Blackman until next week
enjoy
[Music]